Guide to the John L. Margrave academic papers, 1952-1995 MS 505
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series XI: Rice University, 1970-1989, 220479
  - Graduate Office, 220582 (Box 34, Folder 44)
  - Graduate Program, 220581 (Box 34, Folder 45)
  - Graduate Student Financial Support, 220580 (Box 34, Folder 46)
  - Graduate Student Orientation, 220579 (Box 34, Folder 47)
  - Graduate Tuition, 220578 (Box 34, Folder 48)
  - History Department, 220577 (Box 34, Folder 49)
  - ICSA, 220576 (Box 34, Folder 50)
  - Industrial Innovation Conference, 220575 (Box 34, Folder 51)
  - McCrone Agreement (Electron Spectrometer System), 220574 (Box 34, Folder 52)
  - Mathematics Department, 220573 (Box 34, Folder 53)
  - Natural Science Department, 220572 (Box 34, Folder 54)
  - New Faculty Orientation, 220571 (Box 34, Folder 55)
  - NIH Site Visit, 220570 (Box 34, Folder 56)
  - Office of Special Programs, 220569 (Box 34, Folder 57)
  - Philosophy Department, 220568 (Box 34, Folder 58)
  - Physical Plant Department, 220567 (Box 34, Folder 59)
  - Physics Department, 220566 (Box 34, Folder 60)
  - Political Science Department, 220565 (Box 34, Folder 61)
  - Pollak v. Rice, Appendices (Religious Discrimination in Employment), 220564 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Pollak v. Rice, Correspondence, 220563 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Pollak v. Rice, EEOC Charge, 220562 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Pollak v. Rice, Interrogatories, 220561 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Pollak v. Rice, Miscellaneous, 220560 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Pollak v. Rice, Pre-Trial Order, 220559 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Pollak v. Rice, Summons, 220558 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - President's Office, 220557 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Proctor's Office, 220556 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Program for Service to Industry and Business, 220555 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Promotions and Funding, 220554 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Provost's Office, 220553 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Psychology Department, 220552 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Quantum Institute, 220551 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Research Institute Task Force, 220550 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - REDDI, 220549 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Registrar, 220548 (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Religious Studies Department, 220547 (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Report of the Ad Hoc Committee on the Core Curriculum, 220546 (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Research Council, Correspondence, 220545 (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - Research Council, Minutes, 220544 (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - Research Council, Miscellaneous, 220543 (Box 35, Folder 22)
  - Research Council, Report, 220542 (Box 35, Folder 23)
  - Rice Center, Correspondence, 220541 (Box 35, Folder 24)
  - Rice Center, Minutes, 220540 (Box 35, Folder 25)
  - "Rice Today---1980", 220539 (Box 35, Folder 26)
  - Self-Study Panel on Student Affairs, 220538 (Box 35, Folder 27)
  - Seminars, Energy, 220537 (Box 35, Folder 28)
  - Seminars, For In-Service Teachers, 220536 (Box 35, Folder 29)
  - Seminars, Foreign Policy, 220535 (Box 35, Folder 30)
  - Seminars, "Form and Self in Poetry", 220534 (Box 35, Folder 31)
  - Seminars, Ground Water Quality Research, 220533 (Box 35, Folder 32)
  - Shepherd School of Music, 220532 (Box 35, Folder 33)
  - Sigma Xi, 220531 (Box 35, Folder 34)
  - Smithsonian Lecture Program, 220530 (Box 35, Folder 35)
  - Society of Rice University Women, 220529 (Box 35, Folder 36)
  - Sociology Department, 220528 (Box 35, Folder 37)
  - Space Physics and Astronomy Department, 220527 (Box 35, Folder 38)
  - Space Solar Power Research Program, Steering Committee, 220526 (Box 35, Folder 39)
  - Staff Meetings, Correspondence, 220525 (Box 35, Folder 40)
  - Staff Meetings, Minutes, 220524 (Box 35, Folder 41)
  - Staff Meetings, Miscellaneous, 220523 (Box 35, Folder 42)
  - Teacher Education Center Proposal, 220522 (Box 35, Folder 43)
  - University Council, Correspondence, 220521 (Box 35, Folder 44)
  - University Council, Minutes, 220520 (Box 35, Folder 45)
  - University Council, Miscellaneous, 220519 (Box 35, Folder 46)
  - University Council, Promotions, 220518 (Box 35, Folder 47)
  - University Fund Council, 220517 (Box 35, Folder 48)
  - University Research Council, Correspondence, 220516 (Box 35, Folder 49)
  - University Research Council, Minutes, 220515 (Box 35, Folder 50)
  - University Research Council, Miscellaneous, 220514 (Box 35, Folder 51)
  - Visitors, Chiao Tung University, 220513 (Box 35, Folder 52)
  - Visitors, Diamond Shamrock, 220512 (Box 35, Folder 53)
  - Visitors, Dobrynin, Valery, 220511 (Box 35, Folder 54)
  - Visitors, German Journalists, 220510 (Box 35, Folder 55)
  - Visitors, Mattel Toys, 220509 (Box 35, Folder 56)
  - Visitors, Metzger, Dr. Jacques, 220508 (Box 35, Folder 57)
  - Visitors, Nanjing University, 220507 (Box 35, Folder 58)
  - Visitors, New York University, 220506 (Box 35, Folder 59)
  - Visitors, NRL, 220505 (Box 35, Folder 60)
  - Visitors, NSF, 220504 (Box 35, Folder 61)
  - Visitors, PRC [People's Republic of China?] Delegation, 220503 (Box 35, Folder 62)
  - Visitors, Swiss Science Council, 220502 (Box 35, Folder 63)
  - Welch Foundation, 220501 (Box 35, Folder 64)
  - General chronological correspondence:, 220480
    - 1973-1975, 220500 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - January-March 1976, 220499 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - April-June 1976, 220498 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - July-August 1976, 220497 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - September-December 1976, 220496 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - January-February 1977, 220495 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - March-June 1977, 220494 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - July-September 1977, 220493 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - October-December 1977, 220492 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - January-February 1978, 220491 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - March-May 1978, 220490 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - June-August 1978, 220489 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - September-December 1978, 220488 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - January-March 1979, 220487 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - April-June 1979, 220486 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - July-September 1979, 220485 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - October 1979, 220484 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - November-December 1979, 220483 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - 1980-1986, 220482 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Undated, 220481 (Box 37, Folder 5)
- Series XII: Subject Files, 1952-1996, 220393
  Within the series Subject Files are materials of a miscellaneous nature that did not fit into any other series category. This includes abstracts by persons other than Margrave; correspondence, minutes, reports, publications, and newsletters of organizations like the American Chemical Society and the National Academy of Sciences; JANAF tables for 1976-1978; and documents related to the various patents granted to Margrave.
  Researchers should note that a majority of the material in this series is not dated.
  - 1971 Margrave Visitations, 220478 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Abstracts (Not Margrave), 220477 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - ACS, 220476 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - ACS, Correspondence, 220475 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - ACS, Minutes, 220474 (Box 38, Folder 5-6)
  - ACS, Newsletters, 220473 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - ACS, Publications, 220472 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - ACS, Reports, 220471 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - ACS, Symposia, 220470 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - AIC, The Chemist, 220469 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - AWU, Financial Statements, 220468 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Ceramics for F2/HF Lasers, 220467 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - CFX Corporation, 220466 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Chemical Magic, 220465 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Chemical Measurements, 220464 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Delphi Project for Undergraduate Education, 220463 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Disordered Carbons, 220462 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Dow Chemical JANAF Tables, June 30, 1976, 220461 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Dow Chemical JANAF Tables, June 30, 1977, 220460 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Dow Chemical JANAF Tables, March 31, 1978, 220459 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - Dow Chemical JANAF Tables, June 30, 1978, 220458 (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - Dow Chemical JANAF Tables, Miscellaneous, 220457 (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - Electronegativity, 220456 (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - Federation of American Scientists, 220455 (Box 38, Folder 25)
  - Fiber Optic Artwork, 220454 (Box 38, Folder 26)
  - Halo, Helo, and Optical Mirrors, 220453 (Box 38, Folder 27)
  - High Current Brushes, 220452 (Box 38, Folder 28)
  - High Pressure Chemistry, 220451 (Box 38, Folder 29)
  - Houston Philosophical Society, 220450 (Box 38, Folder 30)
  - Hydrolysis Products of Metal-pentane, 220449 (Box 38, Folder 31)
  - Intelligent Processing of Carbon-Carbon Composites, Final Technical Report, 220448 (Box 38, Folder 32)
  - Intra-Science Research Foundation, 220447 (Box 38, Folder 33)
  - Invoices, 220446 (Box 38, Folder 34)
  - Items in Safe, March 1971, 220445 (Box 38, Folder 35)
  - King Faisal International Prize in Science, 220444 (Box 38, Folder 36)
  - Laser Concepts, 220443 (Box 38, Folder 37)
  - Latin American Scholarship Program (LASPAU), 220442 (Box 38, Folder 38)
  - Methylation Studies, 220441 (Box 38, Folder 39)
  - MRC Questions, 220440 (Box 38, Folder 40)
  - NAS, Constitution and Bylaws, 1973, 220439 (Box 38, Folder 41)
  - NAS, Correspondence, 220438 (Box 38, Folder 42)
  - NAS, Elections, 220437 (Box 38, Folder 43)
  - NAS, Membership, 220436 (Box 38, Folder 44)
  - NAS, Minutes, 220435 (Box 38, Folder 45)
  - NAS, Report, 220434 (Box 38, Folder 46)
  - National Board on Graduate Education, Correspondence, 220433 (Box 38, Folder 47)
  - National Board on Graduate Education, Miscellaneous, 220432 (Box 38, Folder 48)
  - New Ideas, 220431 (Box 38, Folder 49)
  - Newsclippings, 220430 (Box 38, Folder 50)
  - Notes, 220429 (Box 38, Folder 51-52)
  - NSF, Correspondence, 220428 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - NSF, Letters to Members, 220427 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - NSF, Miscellaneous, 220426 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - NSF, News, 220425 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - NSF, Nominations for, Correspondence, 1977-1978, 220424 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - NSF, Nominations for, Correspondence, 1979-1981, 220423 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - NSF, Nominations for, Miscellaneous, 220422 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - NSF, Nominations for, Proposals, 220421 (Box 39, Folder 8-12)
  - NSF, Reports, 220420 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - NSF, Reports, Treasurer, 220419 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - NSF, Statements, 220418 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Outstanding Educators of America, 220417 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Patents, 220416 (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Patents, Correspondence, 220415 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Patents, Legal Documents, 220414 (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Patents, Miscellaneous, 220413 (Box 39, Folder 20-21)
  - Philosophical Society of Texas, 220412 (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Product Descriptions (Magneplane, FluoroKote, CFX), 220411 (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Publications (Miscellaneous), 220410 (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Reagan's Economics---Prospects and Perils, 220409 (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - Research Activities of Margrave (University of Wisconsin), 220408 (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - Research Notebook, 220407 (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - Richard B. Turner Memorial Fund, 220406 (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - Scientists Trained by Margrave, 220405 (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - Solid Source for Fluorine, 220404 (Box 39, Folder 30)
  - Southern Methodist University, Grant Award Policy, 220403 (Box 39, Folder 31)
  - STTF, Newsletters, August 1978-March 1979, 220402 (Box 39, Folder 32)
  - Suggestions for Space Experiments in Material Science, 220401 (Box 39, Folder 33)
  - Theoretical Metal-Water Calculations, 220400 (Box 39, Folder 34)
  - Thermodynamic Properties/Synthesis of Si3N4, 220399 (Box 39, Folder 35)
  - Vacuum Cryogenic Desorption Bolometer, 220398 (Box 39, Folder 36)
  - Various Reports, 220397 (Box 39, Folder 37)
  - Wedding Invitation (Karen and James Kauffman), 220396 (Box 39, Folder 38)
  - Welch Foundation, 220395 (Box 39, Folder 39)
  - Who's Who in Ecology, 220394 (Box 39, Folder 40)
- Series XIII: Writings, 1952-1995, 220339
  This series is made up of Margrave's publications and written papers from 1952 through 1995. Some of these are undated. A complete listing of title is available in the WRC's collection control folder.
  - 1954, 220392 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - 1956, 220391 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - 1960, 220390 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - 1961, 220389 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - 1962, 220388 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - 1964, 220387 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - 1966, 220386 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - 1967, 220385 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - 1968, 220384 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - 1969, 220383 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - 1970, 220382 (Box 40, Folder 11-12)
  - 1971, 220381 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - 1972, 220380 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - 1973, 220379 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - 1974, 220378 (Box 40, Folder 16-17)
  - 1975, 220377 (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - 1976, 220376 (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - 1977, 220375 (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - 1978, 220374 (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - 1979, 220373 (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - 1980, 220372 (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - 1981, 220371 (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - 1982, 220370 (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - 1983, 220369 (Box 40, Folder 26)
  - 1984, 220368 (Box 40, Folder 27)
  - 1985, 220367 (Box 40, Folder 28)
  - 1986, 220366 (Box 40, Folder 29-30)
  - 1987, 220365 (Box 40, Folder 31)
  - 1988, 220364 (Box 40, Folder 32)
  - 1989, 220363 (Box 40, Folder 33)
  - 1990, 220362 (Box 40, Folder 34)
  - 1991, 220361 (Box 40, Folder 35)
  - 1992, 220360 (Box 40, Folder 36)
  - 1993, 220359 (Box 40, Folder 37)
  - 1994, 220358 (Box 40, Folder 38)
  - 1995, 220357 (Box 40, Folder 39)
  - Writing by others, 220354
    - Fusaro, Robert L.; Gisser, H.; Holme, Thomas A.; Hutchinson, John S.; Meier, Paul F.; Petronio, M.; Shapiro, A.; Sliney, Harold E.; Waddington, T. C., Brewer, L.; Chandrasekharaiah, M. S.; Elson, Robert E.; Hornig, Howard C.; Jolly, William L.; Kury, John W.; Ramsey, William J.; Zalkin, Allan., 220356 (Box 40, Folder 40-41)
    - by Frederick Rossini, 220355 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Margrave Publication List, 1952-1977, 220353 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Not Dated, Carbons, 220352 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Not Dated, Coal, 220351 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Not Dated, Diamond Film, 220350 (Box 41, Folder 5-6)
  - Not Dated, Fluorine, 220349 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Not Dated, High Temperature, 220348 (Box 41, Folder 8-10)
  - Not Dated, Infrared Spectra, 220347 (Box 41, Folder 11-12)
  - Not Dated, Levitation, 220346 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Not Dated, Mass Spectrometry, 220345 (Box 41, Folder 14-15)
  - Not Dated, Matrix Isolation, 220344 (Box 41, Folder 16-18)
  - Not Dated, Miscellaneous, 220343 (Box 41, Folder 19-23)
  - Not Dated, Thermodynamic Properties, 220342 (Box 41, Folder 24-26)
  - Not Dated, Ultraviolet Spectra, 220341 (Box 41, Folder 27)
  - Publications on CFX and Fluorocarbon Coatings, 220340 (Box 41, Folder 28)